alielreyes.netlify.app

alielreyes@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/alielreyes/

Front End Developer

Proficient software engineer whose passion lies in creating industry-standard web applications. Demonstrated expertise in learning new pipelines, frameworks, and libraries to help find different approaches for solving problems. Known for code readability, adaptable project planning, and skills in designing user experiences. Extensive experience working closely with a variety of clients, ensuring web applications address pain points and improve company productivity. Strong background in video game engineering mixed with an IT experience allows for a unique perspective on creating applications with users as the primary focus.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages / Libraries / Frameworks : React.js, React Hooks, JavaScript, Cascading Style Sheet (CSS),

HTML5, Bootstrap, MDB, AJAX, PHP, jQuery, Appsheet

Development Tools / Methodologies: Git, GitHub, Visual Studio Code, Model View Controller(MVC),

Terminal, NPM, Netlify, Scrum

CAREER EXPERIENCE

All About Parking, San Jose, CA **Application Support Engineer**

2/2018 - Present

Worked in a corporate level environment providing IT support, tool development, and training material for the company.

- Developed 26 internal applications for operations that directly continued client relationships, improved internal communications, and optimized employee daily tasks.
- Communicated with HR, Operations, Sales, and the CEO to enhance and automate daily tasks by utilizing my skills in JavaScript, Appsheet, and Google Apps Script.
- Created IT department ticket management pipeline by implementing project management tools and automating workflows increasing team productivity by approximately 3 hours per day.
- Constructed 58 visual analytical reports for multiple departments through the use of Data Studio and Google Analytics that resulted in expedited high-level business decisions.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

VGScout, San Jose, CA **5/2020 – 6/2020**

Personal Project

Dynamic application used to search for video game information and community posts.

- Utilized promise object to fetch data from a REST API to load comments, search the video game database and populate the webpage.
- Constructed application by utilizing the design pattern Presentational and Container Components, by decoupling logic from UI the application allows for developers to update and expand functionality easily.
- Developed a search bar feature that dynamically renders suggestions by utilizing Reactjs, resulting in a robust and reusable UI component.

Skate Builder, San Jose, CA

1/2019 - 2/2019

Personal Project

Web application that allows for the user to customize their skateboard in a 3D environment.

- Developed 3D controls by using Reactjs and P5 3D library which allows users to view the product from multiple angles creating a more hands on experience.
- Designed the application by using a mobile first approach, resulting in a product that utilizes responsive design to become accessible to any device.
- Created 3D canvas by utilizing React hooks improving overall component reusability and design.

Performance Evaluation Portal, San Jose, CA **Personal Project**

7/2019 – 12/2019

Created a website that allows employees to view their performance results and for admins to manage its users.

- Organized scripts by executing the MVC design pattern expanding its readability and further functionality.
- Constructed authentication system by utilizing AJAX technique alongside PHP and MySQL database to secure and manage user data.
- Created a page template by using HTML, CSS and JavaScript reducing the need to create new code from scratch.

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Science (BS), Degree in Game Design and Engineering - 2017 Cogswell College, San Jose, CA 95134